PROFILE

Functional Analyst and Programmer of Information Systems. Committed to add value to my deliveries beyond what is expected, with special focus on details.

Self-taught and passionate about acquiring new technical skills, as well as increasing my business knowledge.

I enjoy working within a team, although working independently is one of my strengths.

My main expertise currently lies in development and maintenance of core banking systems.

DETAILS

Location: Buenos Aires, Argentina Passport: Argentinian Date of Birth: 10/02/1983

CONTACT

PHONE NUMBER: +54 11 3525 2406

EMAIL ADDRESS:

juanpabloderoovers@hotmail.com

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/juanpablo-de-roovers/

JUAN PABLO DE ROOVERS

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science - 2004

Universidad Católica de Salta

Associate Degree in Computer Programming - 2002

Universidad Tecnológica Nacional (UTN)

Bachillerato (equivalent to High School diploma) - 2000

Instituto San Ramón Nonato

WORK EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2022

Banco Macro S.A. - Functional Analyst

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Functional and technical analysis and documentation (C#/SQL/Sybase/SQR/Visual Basic 6). Interaction with users and software providers. Testing, production implementation and maintenance of core banking applications. Resolution of production incidents.

2013 - 2015

Accenture S.R.L - Specialist - (working for main Argentinian bank) Buenos Aires, Argentina

Survey processes for core banking system migration project (Mainframe to SAP Banking). Mainframe programs development with COBOL/CICS, with Web Services integration (SOA).

2010 - 2013

Accenture S.R.L - Senior Analyst (working for main Argentinian bank) Buenos Aires, Argentina

Maintenance team management (4 members). Development with COBOL/JCL/CICS. Testing, production implementation and post-implementation support. Direct contact with clients. Production incidents resolution.

2008 - 2010

Accenture S.R.L - Junior Analyst (working for main Argentinian bank) Buenos Aires, Argentina

Programmers team management (2 members). Analysis and technical designs documentation. Development with COBOL/JCL/CICS and testing of core banking applications. Resolution of production incidents. On-call support during overnight batch processing.

2006 - 2010

Accenture S.R.L - Trainee (working for main Argentinian bank) Buenos Aires, Argentina

Development with Cobol/JCL/CICS, documentation and testing of core banking applications (Mainframe platform - IBM OS/2). Files (sequential/VSAM) and database (SQL/DB2) handling. Incidents resolution and system upgrades development.

CONTACT

PHONE NUMBER: +54 11 3525 2406

EMAIL ADDRESS:

juanpabloderoovers@hotmail.com

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/juanpablo-de-roovers/

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

Business English Certificate (BEC) English: B2 Higher - 2014

First Certificate in English (FCE) - 2004

TRAINING

2023 - The Complete 2022 Web Development Bootcamp - Udemy

2022 - Achieve Mastery in Data Structures & Algorithms - Java - Udemy

2022 - Java Multithreading, Concurrency & Performance Optimization - Udemy

2022 - Design Patterns in Java - Udemy

2022 - Full Stack Java Developer - Udemy

2022 - Scrum Grand Master - Universidad Tecnológica Nacional (UTN)

2021 - Machine Learning with Python - Universidad Tecnológica Nacional (UTN)

2020 - Undergraduate Degree in Java Programming - Universidad Tecnológica Nacional (UTN)

2020 - Python 3 - Advanced Level - Universidad Tecnológica Nacional (UTN)

2020 - Development in React JS - Universidad Tecnológica Nacional (UTN)

2015 - Development in Android - Universidad Tecnológica Nacional (UTN)

SKILLS

Programming languages

Java

Javascript

HTML / CSS Python

Visual Basic

SQI

■ C#

COBOL

C / C++

Assembler (MCUs)

Sybase SQL Server (SAP ASE) platform

Stored Procedures

Unix

Hyperion SQR

Mainframe IBM z/OS platform

Serena ChangeMan

CICS

■ BMC Control-M

IBM FileAid

■ IBM DB2

JCI SORT

■ TSO

■ IBM FileAid for DB2 ■ IBM VSAM files

Tools / Software

Eclipse (IDE)

Android Studio (IDE)

MS Visual Studio y VS Code (IDE)

BMC Remedy ITSM

DOS/Batch commands

MS Excel-Word-Outlook-Powerpoint

MS PowerShell

Rational ClearQuest

Rational ClearCase

FTP

GIT